EMAD ALGHAMDI

+966 559996003 • emad.ghamdi@hotmail.com

SUMMARY

Self-motivated and dedicated Project, Contract Manager with over 15 years' experience in manfacturing environments. Broad knowledge encompassing various industries and sectors, site management, technical safety, environmental issues and cost control. IT literate with skills in MS Office and the ability to quickly assimilate new software as required. Demonstrated track record of using initiative, sound troubleshooting and applying best practices to improve efficiency, reduce costs and improve productivity. Respected leader of cohesive teams, employing a collaborative leadership style and sound interpersonal skills to motivate teams toward project objectives.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Environmental Strategy & Training
- Environmental Audit & Assessment
- Waste Management & Recycling
- Health & Safety
- Safety, Fire & Security Training
- Change Management
- Environmental Legislation
- Pollution Control
- Risk Assessment

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Establish ABB-Sadara parts management program (PMP)
- Establish ABB-Sadara customer call center (CCC)
- Upgrade Aramco R&D AC chiller plant lighting system and overall plant to ISO 9001 standards
- Worked with colleagues to achieve company Saudization percentage
- Trained over co-op students to become professional plant operators
- Suggested and implemented a plan to improve chiller plant/cooling tower communication with PTT devices
- Upgraded the Aramco R&D AC chiller plant chemical system resulting in record breaking cost savings

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Angles of Art Operation Manager

Jun 2016 - Date

- Continuously monitoring activity, cost and performance.
- Able to deal professionally with all matters of discipline and grievance procedures
- Introduce all new products and services to the client.
- Dealing with operational issues and preparing the crew for emergency and scheduled shutdowns.

ABB SERVICE CONTRACT MANAGER

Jun 2015 - May 2016

- Serve as the point of contact for customers on contractual matters. Act as contractual "middleman" between company employees and customers, ensuring timely review and approval / reconciliation of variations.
- Acting as sadara project manager (operation & maintenance).
- On all standard and nonstandard contracts, provide redlined recommendations and often negotiate directly with customer attorneys or purchasing staff until consensus has been reached.
- Work with Finance to ensure adherence to broader finance and risk requirements such as revenue recognition, pricing and discounting policies,, export controls etc. May include 'financial engineering' and understanding / evaluating economic impact of terms and term options.

Management

- Ability to overview situations.
- Able to priorities and delegate tasks.
- Competently auditing practices and procedures.
- Keeping abreast of new legislation, government policy, best practice.

Sales

- Ability to compile & analyses Key Performance Indicators.
- Achieve sales strategy and company goals with 39m \$ revenue.
- Introduce all new products and services to the client.
- Preparing letters to client, contractors and vendors requesting approvals and interpretations required to comply

JOHNSON CONTROLS INC

Mar 2008 - May 2015

Aramco Projects Manager O&M (Jan 2012 – May 2015) Major project (CDC - R&Dc - DCP)

- Overall management of the project, with due regard to integration across all areas, developing the project plan and directing resources, maintaining documentation and monitoring and managing schedule and risk.
- Dealing with operational issues and preparing the crew for emergency and scheduled shutdowns.
- Negotiating and resolving issues across all areas, negating impact on other activities, systems and projects.

Planning & Execution

- Work closely with the Maintenance Manager, Technical support groups, Plant Management, facility
 maintenance team and contractors, to ensure that scheduled shutdown maintenance and project
 work is planned and executed in accordance standards and procedures.
- Work with the business area to ensure that agreed timings, durations and budgets are developed for all planned activities.

Workscopes

- Develop robust short and long term workscopes to ensure that maintenance and project related work is completed that will enhance the reliability and profitability of the facility as well as meeting all legal requirements.
- Develop standard job plans for repeatable activities to include; costs, durations, specifications, drawings, mobile equipment, materials, manpower, safety/environmental requirements, special tools and any other special or additional instructions needed.

Documentation

• Ensure that all necessary documentation is developed and stored appropriately, using SAP where necessary. This includes all pre and post documentation, standard work packages, calibration certification, test records and reports.

Temporarily assigned as Project Manager for Aramco Southern Area HARADH GOSP-3 Project to replace old control devices – RENOVATE CONTROL ROOMS

Feb - May 2014

 Coordinating with other contractors to achieve the ETC, and with the main warehouse to confirm ETA of the spare part, managing the project team in configuring all new devices, testing and inspecting all actuators while maintaining safe teamwork.

R&Dc Project Manager (Mar 2008 - Dec 2011)

Contract Administration under O&M

- Supervising All R&Dc Lab and R&D AC Plant and monitoring all HVAC systems (AHU, FCU, EF), preparing daily, monthly and project reports and maintaining positive customer and community relations.
- Check and inspect all major equipment with the operators and technicians during the operation time.
- Obtaining work permits for planned work, coordinating and attending meetings with operations and safety personnel, performing fire drills as safety officer.
- Troubleshooting chilled and condenser water pumps and York centrifugal chillers 1100 TR capacity each, conducting preventative maintenance of all chillers and HVAC equipment and monitoring BMS work station (Metasys-M5) Johnson Controls.
- Preparing all equipment for annual maintenance shutdown according to the Aramco standards.
- Scheduling monthly chiller changeover and housekeeping on all chillers, pumps and cooling tower, maintaining records of all chemicals, supplies, parts and equipment utilized.

• Training new, existing, and returning employees, maintaining a safe and healthy environment and developed safety standards in the AC plant.

BADER AL HUSSAINI

Sep 2005 - Feb 2008

AC Plant Operation Coordinator O&M

- Inspecting all chillers, cooling towers, motors, shafts, water levels, maintaining chillers at set temperature, checking all condenser and chilled water pumps for abnormal sounds or high temperature, following up with maintenance crew as necessary.
- Preparing chillers and cooling tower for the maintenance crew during testing and inspection (T&I), controlling the area during T&I for any hazards, isolating power and following all Aramco health and safety protocols.
- Performing housekeeping in the chiller plant and cooling tower area according to the schedule, troubleshooting as necessary, monitoring and operating all the equipment through the BMS.
- Charging the chiller and cooling tower with Freon/oil as required and greasing the motor.

ALKADI TRUCK BODY FACTORY Private Secretary

Dec 2004 - Sep 2005

• Supporting the manager with all administration tasks including screening and replying to all incoming communication, managing the diary, booking travel and accommodation, writing correspondence and recording meetings as well as deputizing in his absence and ensuring a smooth running office at all times.

AL BADER Jun - Dec 2004

Plant Operator (Dispatcher)

- Receiving and ticketing all underground water problem calls, following up with technicians on rectification
- Maintaining raw and sweet water tank level by inspecting each plant in Doha area, taking readings and checking all parameters.

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

MBABusiness & Finance Administration (On-going)PMPProject Management Professional (2011)Aviation EngineerRoyal Jordanian Air Academy (2004)

- HAZCOM Training Aramco (2006)
- Work Permit Receiver (WPR)
- First Aid Training Aramco (SGH)
- Fire Safety (Loss Prevention)
- Heat Exchangers Cooling Towers (SAP)

- Results and Teamwork without Authority (SAP)
- Overhead Crane Operation (OGT 45 days)
- Water Treatement System Course Aramco
- Summer Program of KFUPM (2001)
- Aramco Program (Summers of 2002/2003)

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth 9th May 1984 **Marital Status** Married

Nationality Saudi Languages Arabic & English